#### WINFRED NGE'NDO MUNGAI

P.O BOX 883, Ruiru Tel: +254 726 025 290

Email: winniemungai97@gmail.com

#### **CAREER PROFILE SUMMARY**

As a resourceful professional with over 2 years of experience managing quality control and quality assurance operation to ensure the company produces products that met the quality set standards, I have a wide-ranging skillset in handling various roles involving production environments. Highlights of my experience include inspecting all the incoming raw materials and packaging materials by conducting visual, analysis, and measurement tests, line clearance before the start of production and change over, carrying out in-process checks at a timely interval by confirming required specifications through visual and analysis, measurement. Quality checks of the finished goods in the warehouse, documentation and updating of inspection results, carrying out chemical and microbial analysis of raw materials and finished products. Laboratory management, preparation of reagents, media, and inventories keeping. Calibration of laboratory equipment and enforcing good laboratory practices. My experiences have exposed me to different working environments within the factory where I effectively eliminated all possible causes of hazards and handled emergencies. I am seeking a position where I can put my expertise into use and improve existing processes and systems in the Quality Assurance Department.

#### **EDUCATION BACKGROUND**

- **Diploma in Food Science & Technology-** P.C Kinyanjui; 2012 to 2014.
- Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education- St Joseph the worker; 2006 to 2009.

#### PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

- Food Safety team member; March 2015
- Occupational Health and Safety; [OHS); April 2015.

#### **KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES ACQUIRED**

- Quality Control: Effective in monitoring quality control by implementing quality control and assurance
  procedures, handling qualitative analysis of the main raw material and end product ensuring that the company
  produces products that meet the set quality standards.
- **Quality Assurance**: Experienced with expertise in preventing mistakes and defects in manufactured products and avoiding problems when delivering solutions or services to customers.
- Laboratory Analysis: I successfully carried out physical-chemical lab analysis that is Acidity, Brix ,pH salt,Sulpher dioxide and moisture content. microbial analysis on raw materials, R.O water and finished products ensure they are within company standard requirements, and enforcing good laboratory practices ISO 17025.
- **Food safety:** enforcing production of safe food by preventing and removing any source of contermination and hazard, Maintaining good personal hygiene, clean production premises, pest control and proper waste disposal
- Documentation: Experienced in facilitating record-keeping and documentation for all incoming raw materials
  and keeping records of analysis done and any occurrence concerning quality control.
- **Detail-oriented:** I value accuracy and ensure every duty I undertake pays close attention to details and captures all the quality and analysis reports.
- **Communication and Interpersonal Skills**: Ability to communicate verbally and non-verbally by being effective and concise when giving presentations to audiences.
- **Analytical Skills:** Able to visualize and solve complicated problems in the best way possible and make accurate and informed decisions.
- ICT Competence: Good command of Microsoft Office applications such as Excel and Word.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

# Quality Control Inspector Burn Manfucturing USA LLC February2022-Present

#### **Duties And Responsibilities**

- Inspection of all the incoming raw materials and packaging materials.
- In process quality checks
- Check,inspect and analyze products against specification sheets
- Perform tests to ensure the quality of products
- Work with the quality analysts in spec sheet development and improvement
- Ensure quality standards process are followed keenly
- Write daily quality report
- Escalate issues on the production floor to shift team lead.

#### **Quality Analyst**

# Sai Pharmaceutical Kenya (Hygiene Division) February 2021 -December 2021 Duties and Responsibilities

- Inspection of all the incoming raw materials and packaging materials
- In-process quality checks during production ensuring they meet the set-in house standards
- Carry out chemical analysis of finished products
- Carry out microbial analysis
- Ensure cleanliness of chemical and microbiology laboratory and equipment
- Ensure proper record-keeping and filling
- Ensuring and maintaining hygiene in the factory premises
- Media preparation, reagents for analysis
- Maintain control samples and their records
- Investigation of market complaints
- Carry out internal audits and GMP training
- Equipment calibration
- Ensure all production employees are using the required PPEs while in production
- To check and ensure offline segregation and packing activity is as per standard procedures
- Perform line clearance before production starts.

#### **Key Achievements**

- Successfully carried out the sampling of raw and packaging materials ensuring they met the set standards
- Effectively carried out a microbial analysis of finished products
- Successfully carried out chemical analysis of finished products
- Maintained proper hygiene in the production process
- Successfully handled market returns, market complaints and identified the root cause
- Successfully supervised the production line offline production while ensuring the standards are adhered to
- Ensured that the raw and packaging materials issued to production are analyzed and approved by the quality department
- Managed to reduce the market return complaint due to proper online checks during production.

#### **Quality Control Analyst Intern**

#### Trufoods Limited Company; March to June 2016

#### **Duties and Responsibilities**

- Inspected all the incoming raw materials and packaged material.
- In processed checks and finished products analysis.
- Carried out physical and chemical lab analysis which involved moisture content, colour, texture, temperature weight, taste smell, salt and pH ensuring they met the sets standards.
- Managed the microbial analysis which involved yeast, moulds, coliforms and E Coil.
- Performed equipment calibration.
- Rejected and removed non-conformities from the process and carried out root cause analysis.
- Maintained records of quality checks through updating the checklist on an hourly basis.
- Maintained quality records and proper filling of test results in compliance with laboratory standards.

- Ensured a high level of hygiene throughout and ensuring the production was maintained.
- Proper disposal of market return products and proper root cause.
- Ensured production was carried out in line with quality control, food safety, GMP and Qc Checks at all stages.

#### **Key Achievements**

- Managed to inspect the incoming and packaging of raw materials for compliance to standards.
- Inspected the quality of online products e.g. Jam making line, Tomato sauce line, canned products, peanut butter processing, that is temperature, texture, color, size taste and foreign matters ensuring no chemical contamination
- Successfully treated micro-organisms and proper disposal of waste, cleaning and sterilization of lab and equipment.
- Successfully ensured all the products conformed to the set standards and fit for consumption.
- Monitored products quality at all stages from receiving of raw materials, packaging, during processing finished products analysis and storage.
- Managed high standards of hygiene & GMP in the entire production floor.

#### **Quality Assurance Supervisor**

#### Njoro Canning Factory; January to June 2015

#### **Duties and Responsibilities**

- Handled customer complaints and ensured customers were satisfied.
- Ensured quality procedures were followed as per ISO standards.
- Properly documented files and filed them and also wrote reports.
- Carried out traceability.
- Released product to the market and issued the COA certificate.
- Enforced food safety and HACCP and ensured government regulations on occupation Health and safety and environmental issue were met.
- Developed cleaning programs.

#### **Key Achievements**

- Gained significant skills in carrying out equipment calibration.
- Successfully managed the laboratory.
- Assessed and monitored the quality of the finished product before dispatch.
- Familiarized myself with Food safety.

#### Quality Analyst Attaché

## Kenya Bureau of Standards (KEBS); November to December 2013

#### **Duties and Responsibilities**

- Cleaned and disinfected benches.
- Carried out Media preparation, inoculation and incubation.
- Handled water analysis using UV light parameters tested, E.coli, coliforms, Staph. And Salmonella.
- Beverages analysis; Ethanol density using pyknometer, brix using refractometer.
- Microbial analysis that was the determination of Yeast, Moulds, Coliforms, E Coli, Salmonella and Staphy.aureaus.
- Physical analysis of various foods; Moisture Content, Acid Insoluble Ash, pH, Acidity, fat content, Free Fatty Acid and the sulphur dioxide and brix.
- Ensured the proper labeling of samples and ensured results were accurate.
- Ensured test requirements were met in stipulated time.

#### **OTHER ENGAGEMENTS**

• **Greengrocer;** Self Employed, January 2019 -January 2020 Maintained grocery store and ensured that it was running smoothly and effectively and also carried out the Quality inspection of fruits and vegetables ensuring they were of high quality upon delivery.

#### **REFEREES**

#### **David Maingi**

Senior Quality Control Analyst Sai Pharmaceutical Limited Tel:+254 727006013

# Lydia Wanjiku

Quality Assurance Manager Trufoods Company

Tel: +254 721336745

### **Brain Simiyu**

Quality Assurance Manager Njoro Canning Factory Tel: +254 727 018 583